http://www.islandinkjet.com/c/privacy/

feedback
Submit
Your feedback has been submitted, thank you for helping to make our site even better!
Our Company
What are "Personal Printers"?
Green
i'm a thing you see!
Privacy Notice
The Equipment Leasing Company Ltd. (Island Ink-Jet) knows that you care how information about you is used and shared, and we appreciate your trust and want you to feel confident in our services and security as it relates to your personal information. This notice describes our privacy policy. By visiting islandinkjet.com, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Notice.
What Personal Information About Customers Does Island Ink-Jet Gather?
The information we learn from customers helps us personalize and continually improve our Technical Support communication. Here are the types of information we gather.
Information You Give Us
We receive and store any information you enter on our Web site or give us in any other way. You can choose not to provide certain information, but then you might not be able to take advantage of many of our features. We use the information that you provide for such purposes as responding to your requests, improving our support features and communication with you.
Electronic Information
We use Google Analytics, Google AdWords Conversion tracker, and other Google services that place cookies on a browser across the website.
We receive and store certain types of information whenever you interact with our website. For example, like many web sites, we sometimes use "cookies," and we obtain certain types of information when your web browser accesses our website.
Google Analytics uses "cookies" to collect standard internet log information and visitor behaviour information in an anonymous form. No personally identifiable information is collected about you unless you explicitly submit that information via a fill-in form on this website. The anonymous information generated by Google Analytics cookies about your use of this website is transmitted to Google. This information is then processed to compile statistical reports, used to evaluate visitor usage so that we can optimise the content to better meet your needs.
What Are Cookies?
Cookies help us serve you better by providing operational data that assists us in improving the functionality and performance of our website.
The use of cookies and similar technologies is a common internet practice, allowing websites to recognize your device, keep track of pages you have visited, and remember personal preferences for your convenience.
You may refuse to accept cookies by accessing the privacy settings on your browser or device, by managing the cookie settings for each browser and device that you use. However, if you do not accept cookies, you may experience inconvenience or difficulties related to efficiency, performance or access when visiting our site.
Remarketing Policy
This website also uses the Google AdWords remarketing service to advertise on third party websites (including Google) to previous visitors to our site. It could mean that we advertise to previous visitors who haven’t completed a task on our site, for example using the contact form to make an enquiry. This could be in the form of an advertisement on the Google search results page, or a site in the Google Display Network. Third-party vendors, including Google, use cookies to serve ads based on someone’s past visits to the islandinkjet.com website.
Any data collected will be used in accordance with our own privacy policy and Google’s privacy policy.
When creating remarketing lists, we do not use any sensitive information about users. This includes information such as their financial status, sexual orientation, and other sensitive categories.
As AdWords advertisers, we are restricted from and will not perform the following actions:
(a) Running ads that collect Personally Identifiable Information (PII) including, but not limited to, email addresses, telephone numbers, and credit card numbers
(b) Creating a remarketing list or creating ad text that specifically targets users in ways that are outlined or described as prohibited by our Privacy Policy.
Visitors can opt out of Google Analytics for Display Advertisers and opt out of customized Google Display Network ads by visiting the Ads Preferences Manager.
What Qualifies as Personal Information?
We consider personal information to be any information about an identifiable individual that is not
public information found in directories or listings containing business names, addresses and/or contact information.
Does Island Ink-Jet Share the Information It Receives?
We share your information with your Island Associate account representative which in most cases is the Island Associate store closest to your home / place of business for use in supporting your requests. We respect your privacy and appreciate your business and at no time do we ever provide your account contact to any third party vendor.
Which Information Can I Access?
Island Ink-Jet, gives you access to a broad range of information about your account and your interactions with us for the limited purpose of viewing and, in certain cases, updating that information.
Conditions of Use, Notices, and Revisions
If you choose to visit Island Ink-Jet your visit and any dispute over privacy is subject to this Notice and our Conditions of Use, including limitations on damages, arbitration of disputes, and application of the law of the Province of Ontario. If you have any concern about privacy of your personal information as used and collected within our website, please send us a thorough description by clicking on Privacy Policy Issue and we will try to resolve it.
Our business changes constantly, and our Privacy Notice and the Conditions of Use will change also. We may e-mail periodic reminders of our notices and conditions, unless you have instructed us not to, but you should check our Web site frequently to see recent changes. Unless stated otherwise, our current Privacy Notice applies to all information that we have about you and your account. We stand behind the promises we make, however, and will never materially change our policies and practices to make them less protective of customer information collected in the past without the consent of affected customers.
Automatic Information
For security purposes Island Ink-Jet sometimes collects and analyzes the Internet protocol (IP) address used to connect your computer to the Internet, and to our website. This is done for your protection for tracking purposes in the unfortunate event that someone gains access to your personal or financial information.
How Can I Be Removed From Your Lists?
If you wish to be removed from our mailing list please notify us by email and let us know what from which list you wish to be removed.
E-Mail:
privacy@islandinkjet.com
Shop by Brand
View All Brands
Browse Departments
Toner Cartridges
Compatible Toner Cartridges
OEM Toner Cartridges
Remanufactured Toner Cartridges
Retail Stores
The Licensed Island Associate Program is an opportunity for you to download the non-revenue generating activities of your small business to the Associate group and gain a new partner that will contribute to the success of your business in a variety of ways also allowing you to focus your time where it should be focused- generating sales.
Our Retail Store Program
Environmental
Recycling is great, but Reusing is better. At Island Ink-Jet we believe in refilling and reusing cartridges whenever possible, before sending them for recycling and replacing them with a new one. Reusing an inkjet cartridge can save the energy and materials used in recycling it, decreasing the overall environmental impact of printing.
Our Environmental Impact
Sales Agents
Why open your own store, carry inventory, manage cash and billing? Becoming an Island Ink-Jet sales agent is like owning a business without any investment required and without having to manage any of the above! What could possibly be better?
Our Sales Agent Program
Free Shipping* & Fast Delivery
*on orders over $49, some restricitons apply
Save OnCopiers(New & Used)
Save Now
SimplifyYour Orders
Why Shop with Island Ink-Jet?
Highest Quality. Low cost. Fast Shipping. Largest Selection. Local expert assistance. Millions of satisfied customers. The list goes on. We are a name you can trust, not simply a website operated by people you will never meet.
Read More
What truly sets us apart from other retailers and especially online stores is that our physical stores are Licensed & independently owned and operated by small business owners in your community.
When you order online at Island Ink-Jet you are supporting the locally owned businesses and economy in your community through our profit sharing model and you in turn receive localized support from those businesses.
No competitor can offer the same degree of localized support, sales and service as we can.
Much like how we pioneered the retail ink refill service, we are pioneering how online sales contribute to the local economy.
Shipping is free on printer cartridge orders of $49 or greater.
We ship out of distribution centres located on the east coast, west coast and a few in between using the best couriers such as FedEx and Purolator, thus ensuring that most orders ship same day and can be delivered the next business day.
Our in-house printer ink and toner cartridges offer industry-leading quality and are ISO 9001 certified.
Returns are hassle-free with no return shipping cost on defective products.
Read Less
About Island Ink-Jet
In 2001 Island Ink-Jet launched our first retail store in Courtenay BC offering North America’s first retail printer cartridge refill service.
The service we pioneered was an instant hit and Island grew to one of the nation’s largest Canadian-owned retail chains in terms of store locations within a few short years.
Read More
Today Island Ink-Jet offers much more than an ink refill service. We are Canada’s leading source of printer ink and toner cartridges (OEM/name brand or compatible).
What may also surprise you is that we also carry a full line of office products (be it office furniture or pens & pencils) to make business procurement that much easier!
We believe that high quality products and services can be delivered to your door in a professional manner with no hassle and in the least amount of time. That’s why we choose to partner with companies like FedEx who get our packages to where they need to go in the least amount of time and without fail – often delivered the next business day.
With stores in most major markets, we believe strongly in the value of “putting a face to the name”. Learn more by visiting our “about us” page.
Read Less
Buy with 100% Confidence!
Our entire website (not just the checkout page) features 256-bit SSL encryption ensuring your purchases are completely secure!
In a time where current “industry standards” are 128-bit – we believe in going the extra mile to ensure your identity is protected.
We also do not spam or resell your contact information.
Rest assured Island Ink-Jet and Laser Toners is a brand you can trust.
Have a look at our policies for more information.
Help
Terms & Conditions
Shipping Policies
Privacy Policies
Shop by Printer
Sitemap
Sitemap (XML)
About Us
About Our Company
FAQs
Contact Us
Business Services
The Environment
Connect and Share
Copyright ©2020. The Equipment Leasing Company Ltd.
All Rights Reserved.
Trademark names used in this website are for identification only. trademarks are the rightful property Of their owners. Island Ink-Jet is not affiliated with any OEM manufacturer.
Share
×
Sign in to Island Ink-Jet
Email
Password
Remember my Email for next time
Cancel
Sign Up
Forgot Password
Sign In
×Close
Submitted - Thanks!
Your contact request has been submitted to our customer service team.
We'll get back to you as soon as possible!
OK
×Close
Island Ink-Jet Pricing Policy
Prices quoted on this website including any discounts found are available only when ordering online. We make every effort to keep our online prices competitive with the online marketplace.
In-store pricing and availability will differ from Island Ink-Jet online sites.
In-store pricing will usually be higher compared to prices quoted on this website due in part to the value-added service provided in-store and the additional costs incurred by the store while providing those value-added services.
It is a generally understood principle that companies can offer lower prices online due the lower costs incurred in providing an online shopping experience.
Here are some of the value added services consumers receive by buying in store: Product is available for immediate pick-up; consumers are able to deal face to face with an expert who can provide guidance, advice and troubleshooting tips; immediate resolution to any issues. Ancillary benefits include your support of your the local economy. It is noted that stores incur additional expenses such as rent, labour, overhead which make it impossible to offer the online price in store.
Island Ink-Jet cannot confirm the price of an item until after your order is placed.
Pricing errors may occur on the Island Ink-Jet website and Island Ink-Jet reserves the right to cancel any orders containing pricing errors, with no further obligations to you, even after your receipt of an order confirmation or shipping notice from Island Ink-Jet.
Island Ink-Jet may, at its discretion, either contact you for instructions or cancel your order and notify you of such cancellation.
Close
×Close
Island Ink-Jet Shipping Policy
General Info
Orders received Monday to Friday before 2pm eastern are processed and shipped same day. Orders placed after 2pm on Friday or on Saturday or Sunday will be processed the following Monday. Delivery can take 1-5 business days and customer will receive tracking number to confirm shipment once order has left our warehouse(s).
Orders are shipped by courier (FedEx/Purolator) from any of our 8 distribution centres based on proximity of the items ordered to your door. It is common for most densely populated areas to receive their orders the next business day. Certain factors may contribute to orders taking up to 5 days such as availability of the items ordered at the closest distribution centre.
Special order items or orders placed outside of the local trading areas may take 5 or more business days to ship and can have a separate delivery charge based on the weight and delivery distance of the order.
In the event of a holiday, deliveries may be delayed. We observe many Federal and Provincial holidays across Canada.
If you are in an area that is observing a holiday and are unsure of your delivery date, please contact us.
Processing fees
In some cases an order cannot be filled by a single distribution centre such as if an order for two items is placed and only one is in stock at the closest distribution centre yet a second is available within another of our facilities. When this occurs, the order is processed to be shipped in its entirety from as many points as necessary to fill the order and have it arrive at your door in the least amount of time. Should this occur, only one processing fee may apply even if the order is processed to ship from several distribution centres. A processing fee will be visible during checkout (on the check-out screen) if applicable.
Shipping Charges
Our standard shipping charge applies on all orders, and is a flat rate of $8.50 Shipping costs are waived on all orders of $49 or more*.
*Free shipping not available in the Canadian Territories of Yukon, North West Territories and Nunavut
*"Free shipping” offer does not apply to oversized items including printers and copiers, office furniture. Shipping charges may apply and are billed/charged at time of shipping based on the actual cost of freight to destination. Contact us at 1-877-446-5538 if shipping quotes are required prior to purchase.
Delivery
Island Ink-Jet is not liable for delivery exceptions that may occur due to storms, natural disasters, receiving incomplete addresses or when the customer is unavailable to accept the delivery.
The Customer accepts that couriers will attempt delivery as requested by the Customer and should the Customer be unavailable to accept the delivery; the goods shall be physically deposited at the address.
Notwithstanding the above a notification may be left at the door advising that a second delivery attempt will be made or to provide instruction on how to pick up locally thereafter.
In the unlikely event that the package continues to remain unclaimed by the customer over the course of the following 10 days – it will be returned to the originating warehouse.
Returned shipments are eligible for refund however all actual shipping costs incurred (on both outbound and inbound shipments) are at the customers expense and will be subtracted from any refund provided.
The goods shall be deemed to have been delivered when they are physically deposited at the address given to the Company by the Customer or consignee for that purpose, or have been collected from the Company’s premises or an authorised agent of the Company.
The Customer accepts that no form of acknowledgement or signature that delivery has occurred is required to be obtained by the courier except in those instances where the Customer has specified, and the Company has agreed, that the Company obtain proof of delivery.
In the unlikely event that goods are lost after having been delivered, the Customer is advised to report the theft to local authorities and their insurance provider.
Store Pick-Up
Orders cannot be placed online for pick-up at one of our retail stores. Should you wish to pick up items, please contact your local retail store directly and they will be happy to assist.
P.O. Boxes
Most couriers cannot deliver to Canada Post office boxes.
Goods shipped to P.O. Boxes may incur additional delivery time.
In some cases entire product lines are ineligible for shipment to a P.O. Box.
Customers are advised to confirm that goods can be delivered to a P.O. Box prior to submitting their order.
Goods are shipped to the address provided by the Customer without review and if the address provided contains a P.O. Box – the goods will be shipped to that address despite the Post Office potential to decline the goods.
Goods shipped to a P.O. Box that are later returned to our warehouse are eligible for refund less a flat rate shipping cost incurred of $14.50.
You may contact us by email at sales@islandinkjet.com or call us at 1-877-446-5538 from 9am to 5pm EST Monday through Friday. A customer service representative will be happy to assist you.
Close
×
Like us on Facebook and save today!
Like us and get 5% off
Apply Now
Coupon is valid for 90 days and for online purchases only. Offer excludes Original Equipment Manufacturer (OEM) Ink and Toner Cartridges. Cannot be combined with other offers.
Like us on Facebook and get 5% off your purchase.
Our fans recieve exclusive discounts and offers. -
Already Like Island Ink-Jet?
Searching...
Searching products... please wait...
Scheduled Maintenance
Please note, Island Ink-Jet's website will be down at 8:00pm Saturday September 16th for regular maintenance.
Please complete any transactions prior to that time.
